camper.com 2016-04-20

# Camper. Legal Information and Privacy Policy.

RURALMED, S.L. and its subsidiary companies (hereinafter “CAMPER“, “we“, “our“, “us“) respect the privacy rights of its online visitors (“you”, “your”, “yours”) and recognize the importance of protecting the information collected about them. CAMPER has adopted a corporate wide Privacy Policy that guides how we collect, store and use the information that you provide us with. 

If you are under 18, you must inform a parent or guardian about CAMPER’s Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions and they must consent to the Privacy Policy and Terms and Conditions before registering with CAMPER or placing an order with CAMPER.

The following information is provided by CAMPER to enable you to be fully informed of our Privacy Policies. By visiting CAMPER.COM you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this Privacy Policy and the Terms and Conditions. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy and/or the Terms and Conditions, please do not further access and/or use the website.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we link. CAMPER is not responsible for any personal information you submit to third parties via our website. Please ensure that you read the Privacy Policy of such other companies or organizations before submitting your details. 

### What information do we collect from you and how?

CAMPER collects personal information in several ways when you place an order, take part in competitions, promotions and/or other activities in which you are requested to provide this information. When an order is placed with CAMPER, we need to hold personal information including your name, address email address, phone numbers, shipping and credit card billing address(es) so that we can process and fulfill your order. Additionally, we may also obtain information as a result of authentication or identity checks. If you wish to be included on our mailing list, we will ask you to give us your prior authorization.

Similarly, when you visit our website, we will collect the data known as “clickstreams”(server address, domain name, etc). This information, combined with details you have provided us with enables us to customize your next visits better.

Your personal information is only retained for a period reasonably necessary to meet the purposes for which it is collected. 

### How this information may be used

CAMPER may use your personal information for the processing of orders and payment. We will also use your details to fulfill and deliver your orders and manage your account. Personal information that you provide may be disclosed to a credit reference or fraud prevention agency, which may keep a record of that information. 

Your personal information provided for the purposes of processing and delivery of your order will be used according to the provisions of the Terms and Conditions.

We may use your information for organizing events, drawing up statistics or other website functions as well as for providing you with the services available on the website. Where there is a legal obligation to do so, we may disclose you information to any relevant regulatory body. We may also disclose your information in response to a valid, legally compliant request by a competent authority or in response to a court order or otherwise in compliance with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request or other statutory requirement; to enforce the Terms and Conditions including the investigation of potential violations thereof; to detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect against imminent harm to the rights and property of CAMPER.

We may also use your personal information to send you information and materials by e-mail and/or SMS, including product details and special offers and newsletters that we consider may be of interest to you. These may either be related to our products or those of our trading partners and/or Licensees. This information will only be sent to you if you have given us your specific prior authorization.

In addition we may use your personal information for analyzing the visits to the website and determining the individual and overall interests of visitors to the website. This provides us with information that enables us to improve the products, services, functions, promotions that may be of most interest to you and the design of the website to better meet our visitors’ needs. 

Furthermore, we also collect your personal details through the different forms contained on the website, so that you can process cancellations, returns and/or exchanges in relation to products purchased from CAMPER, and in order for us to be able to reply to your queries, to send you our newsletter, to deal with your claims and if requested and authorized by you, to include you in the recruitment processes organized by CAMPER to work in its offices or stores.

Finally, you are hereby informed that if you fill in the form to join the CAMPER FRIENDS loyalty scheme, your personal details will be used to send you details of our products and any other matters of interest related to CAMPER. You are also informed that we may send you surveys for the purpose of improving our services. 

### Opt-in provision

When you register, we will provide a link to the Privacy Policy and consent button for the collection of personal data.

In addition you will be given the option to an opt-in of subscribing to:

Our regular newsletter which will be sent by email to you with respect to new products, features, enhancements, special offers, upgrade opportunities, contests and events of interest. Such alerts may include marketing information about CAMPER, our subsidiaries or selected business partners; and/or one-off marketing promotions from us. 

At all times, you can unsubscribe out of any service or update to which you have subscribed. Any e-mail or newsletter which we send will contain an easy automatic unsubscribe link so that you can opt-out.

### Protection of information

We use our best endeavors to maintain appropriate safeguards to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of the information you have provided us with. To guarantee the security of your details we have set in place a series of security measures and safeguards. Your personal details are stored on secure networks that may only be accessed by a limited number of persons holding special access rights and who undertake to respect and maintain the confidential nature of this information. In addition we will take reasonable steps to ensure that third party business partners’ to whom we transfer any data will provide sufficient protection of that personal information.

Despite these measures, whenever you provide your personal details on the Internet, there is a risk that this information may be intercepted and used by third persons whom we are unable to control. Although CAMPER makes every effort to protect your personal details and privacy, we are unable to guarantee the security of this information which you make available over the Internet at your own risk.

### Third parties

Your details may be transferred to partners that host our websites and third parties who assist us in the design and use of the website, or provide us with services or analyze data collected. These third parties will use the data for the purposes of carrying out the tasks described above, and undertake to respect and maintain the personal details when required to do so by law. In addition your details may be transferred to companies that form part of our group (if you would like further information about these companies, please click here) and for the purposes described earlier in this Privacy Policy; if you do not want to receive information from these companies, please send us an e-mail to customercare@camper.es. Other than in these cases, we do not sell, trade or transfer your personal details in any form to third parties without informing you first and in accordance with the data protection legislation currently in effect.

### Hyperlinks

We may include hyperlinks on this website to other websites or resources operated by third parties other than CAMPER, including advertisers. CAMPER has not reviewed all of these websites linked to this website and is not responsible for the content or accuracy of any off-site pages nor are we responsible for the availability of such external websites or resources, and do not endorse and are not responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for the privacy practices or the content of such websites, including (without limitation) any advertising, products or other materials or services on or available from such websites or resources, nor for any damage, loss or offence caused or alleged to be caused by, or in connection with, the use of or reliance on any such content, goods or services available on such external websites or resources.

### Cookies

During your visit to the website, CAMPER may collect information using cookies. A cookie is a small text file that a server can place on a user’s computer’s hard disk. It contains information about the user’s website visit. Cookies can be used to compile specific information during your visit to the website. This information can help CAMPER to ensure that the website and the services are as closely adapted as possible to its users’ needs and preferences. In view of this, we would like to inform you that you may find the following types of cookies: 

CAMPER'S OWN COOKIES   
---  
Type  |  Denomination  |  Technical name  |  Domain  |  Description   
Identification  |  User session ID  |  JSESSIONID  |  www.camper.com  |  User's session ID. It is thus possible to identify the different requests that a user might make during the current session. It is deleted at the end of the session   
Browsing  |  Browser Cookies  |  __camperCountry  |  www.camper.com  |  Browser country detection. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
__camperGeoCountry  |  www.camper.com  |  Country detection via browser IP. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
__camperLang  |  www.camper.com  |  It detects the language and guarantees that it is not changed during the session. It is deleted after one month.   
__camperShowPopUpNews  |  www.camper.com  |  It shows associated information to users who have subscribed to our newsletters. If they are not subscribers, no information associated with newsletters is shown. It is deleted after seven days.   
Website location  |  __mxsv  |  .camper.com  |  Detecting user's location during the browsing and the purchasing process. It thus provides support for Google Analytics' tracking. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
Drupal JS-Elemente  |  has_js  |  www.camper.com  |  This cookie informs the system about whether JavaScript is enabled in the browser being utilized by the user. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
EXTERNAL COOKIES   
Type  |  Denomination  |  Technical name  |  Domain  |  Description   
Identification  |  Userzoom.com  |  AWSELB  |  cdn3.userzoom.com  |  It enables users of other websites to conduct surveys. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
Analysis  |  Browsing analysis  |  __utma  |  .camper.com  |  They make it possible to monitor user access to the website using the Google Analytics tool. You can find further information at: https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage   
__utmb  |  .camper.com   
__utmc  |  .camper.com   
__utmz  |  .camper.com   
__utmz0  |  .camper.com   
Advertising  |  .w55c.net  |  matchgoogle  |  .w55c.net  |  It makes it possible to delimit the advertising offered to the users at other sites. It is deleted at the end of the month   
wfivefivec  |  .w55c.net  |  It makes it possible to delimit the advertising offered to the users at other sites. It is deleted after two years.   
apis.google.com  |  NID  |  .google.com  |  Google uses these cookies to customize the advertisements that are shown in Google's services, such as, for example, Google Search, especially when a session has not been initiated with a Google account. The cookies are also used to show advertisements beyond Google. They are deleted after six months.   
accounts.google.com  |  NID  |  .google.com   
web.epartner.es  |  _pf_  |  web.epartner.es  |  It makes it possible to register browsing preferences for advertising purposes. It is deleted after three months.   
Affilinet  |  affili_10508  |  affili.net/  |  It makes it possible to control the time that elapses after clicking on the website. It also makes it possible to identify the publisher of the selected link. It is deleted after thirty days.   
affili_10508pv  |  affili.net/  |  It makes it possible to control the time that elapses after displaying the contents of the website. It also makes it possible to identify the publisher of the selected link. It is deleted after thirty days.   
ASP.NET_SessionId  |  affili.net/  |  It makes it possible to maintain the session with Affilinet's server. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
Browsing  |  paypal  |  DC  |  www.paypal.com  |  This cookie is generated on downloading Paypal's corporate image. It is deleted at the end of the session.   
static.ak.facebook.com  |  no cookies  |  www.facebook.com  |  Refer to www.facebook.com   
s-static.ak.facebook.com  |  no cookies   
www.facebook.com  |  no cookies   
  
You can set up the Internet browser so that it informs you every time that a new cookie is stored in the computer; this will enable you to decide whether to accept it or reject it. Please go to your Internet browser’s help section for specific instructions. 

Please do not forget that some parts of the website may not function correctly if you reject the cookies.

### Reviewing, editing and deleting your data

Under the terms of the applicable data protection rules and legislation you are entitled to inspect, correct and/or delete any personal data concerning you, as well as to revoke your consent to receive information about promotions and other matters of interest related to CAMPER, at any time. To this end you may address a request for such inspection, correction, deletion and/or objection to Ruralmed S.L. (CAMPER) Att.: department Web y SAC, Polígono Industrial s/n, 07300 Inca, Mallorca, Islas Baleares, Spain. Or by e-mail at the following address: [customercare@camper.es](mailto:customercare@camper.es). 

To allow, know, block or delete the installed cookies on your computer, you can do it by changing your setting options on your computer’s browser. 

### Changes to the Privacy Policy

CAMPER reserves the rights to amend, modify and/or replace all or part of this website and the information and materials contained on it, as well as this Privacy Policy. Please check this Privacy Policy periodically for changes or modifications.

### No waiver

In case CAMPER does not enforce any of the provisions set forth above, this will not be understood in any manner as a waiver to such provisions.

©CAMPER, March 2011
